what's up everyone it's C with money
vest so we had the inflation numbers
coming out earlier today about exactly
12 and a half hours ago we had the
inflation numbers I did a live stream
during that time to go over all the
numbers and we also talked about the
Market's reaction and how it's going to
become increasingly difficult for uh
shelter prices for inflation numbers to
now make this last leg lower from 4%
down to as low as 2% which is what the
Federal reserve's target really is so
I'm going to break down we've got lots
lots to unpack in this video as always
if you enjoy it find it helpful make
sure that you drop a like and don't
forget to subscribe to the channel and
of course link to our Discord and
patreon is going to be down below if
you're interested in joining us and of
course being a part of our money vest
Community uh again I've did open up a
couple more spots in October and you
will get access to all the Excel
spreadsheets that are available to
download you'll get EX access to members
only private videos that you can watch
at your own free time and you will get
access to the money vest stock reports
and not to mention over 18 to 20 private
Discord channels including buy alerts
options alerts trade ideas and uh
everything is going to be included with
the link down below and we'll love to
have you on board and there's a lot of
analysis and a lot of discussions that
are happening on individual companies as
well that you can access through sad as
well now going over to the markets the
state of the markets the Dow Jones here
dropping over 76 basis points the NASDAQ
and the S&B also rolling over here
pretty aggressively uh we did sort of we
were drifting a little bit higher after
the inflation numbers came out we did
drop then we recovered a little bit uh
and then we rolled right back down uh we
did have over 1,900 stocks down between
0 and 2% another 1,600 that were down
between 2 and 5% and overall we had over
4,500 stocks that were declining on the
day with about almost a th000 stocks
that were neutral and just about 1400
stocks that were advancing and green on
the day so here are the CPI numbers uh
month over month coming in a little bit
hotter than what the expectations were
at0 4% year-over year coming at 3.7%
which was a little bit higher than what
the consensus was and in line with the
previous number and core CPI when you
exclude for food and energy coming in 3%
month over month and 4.1% year-over-year
that was in line with what the consensus
really was um from the market so we got
two numbers coming in hotter than
expectations two numbers coming in line
with expectations um so overall there it
was a bit of a mixed report but if you
really break it down into some of the
categories that were released which I'll
go over in just a minute Energy prices
higher especially fuel oil up over 8 and
a half% month over month which was not a
surprise something that we were talking
about in our previous updates
and and the shelter prices were up 6% on
a month over Monon basis I think this is
really where the uh a lot of the problem
lies and that is going to be in the real
estate market more specifically shelter
and rents um that are not really coming
down in fact we did a poll with all the
members we had over you know 600 people
700 people watching yesterday earlier
today in our live stream and I asked
everyone right if you are a homeowner if
you are a real estate investor if you
are a tenant what are you actually
witnessing in the rental market market
and everybody mentioned the rents are
going up they're not going down not a
single person I think I can remember
said their rents are indeed lower they
are all they all pretty much mentioned
their rents were higher from same time
last year and they are consistently
going up um as property taxes around the
country has risen uh not to mention that
interest rates are at an extreme level
at over 78% we haven't seen these rates
in over 23 years uh and because of that
the gap between the actual buyers and
sellers the Gap is the the highest that
we have seen in a very long time um and
as I mentioned during the live stream as
well I was on the call with one of my
friends who's a real estate agent uh in
the in the east coast and he mentioned
that the sellers are not willing to
budge in other words they're too
stubborn to lower their prices and on
the other hand the buyers can't afford
such high prices given how high the
interest rates are so there's the
biggest Gap that we've seen with between
buyers and sellers when it comes to real
estate so that I think will need to
resolve itself over time before we start
to see rents falling over and that's one
of the reasons why I've mentioned before
that it's a lot easier it's it's
significantly easier for the Federal
Reserve to bring inflation down from 9
to 4% but this last leg right which is
the last sort of Mile basically coming
down from 4 to two is the most difficult
thing because prices tend to be stickier
in certain areas more than others and
for that reason it's going to be a
challenge for the Federal Reserve to
really really bring inflation down to 2%
and this was an article that came out
earlier today so getting to 2% inflation
won't be easy and this is what will need
to happen and it might not be pretty so
in theory getting inflation closer to
the federal reserve's 2% Target doesn't
sound terribly difficult and it doesn't
right in theory doesn't the main
culprits are related to services and
shelter cost with many of the other
components showing noticeable signs of
easing so targeting just two areas of
the economy doesn't seem like uh the
gargantuan task compared to say the
summer of 2022 when basically everything
was going up in practice though it could
be harder than it looks and prices in
those two pivotal components have proven
to be stickier than food and gas or even
used cars or new cars and all of which
tend to be cyclical as they rise and
fall with the ABS and flows of the
broader economy so that's exactly my
point some prices especially Services
shelter cost they tend to be a lot more
stickier than that of food and food and
gas they're tend to be more volatile and
uh this right here was Steven Blitz a
chief of of us Economist at global data
TS Lombard and he says and I quote you
need a recession you're not going to
magically get down to 2% and that's the
whole idea right I mean getting down to
2% is going to be tough and we've talked
about this I think I mentioned this like
literally six months ago eight months
ago in my one of my videos where um
getting down from 9 to 4 easy getting
from 4 to two incredibly difficult and
in order to get down to that level I
think there is a very good case to be
made that overall consumer spending just
needs to come down and rents needs to
come down and a lot of the stickier
items you know Energy prices we've
already discussed but food prices and uh
apparel right a lot of the components on
inflation need to roll over and a lot of
these things will come down if there is
a recession and look that's unfortunate
but it's kind of again in one of those
situations where bad news for the
economy ends up good being good news for
the market because the sooner inflation
gets down to 2% the sooner the Federal
Reserve is going to start looking at
cutting rates and that will eventually
lead to some quantitative easing and
some and a very significant bullish
Catalyst for the market now there was
also a discussion in the market uh live
stream that we had there was a very
interesting question from Tristan he
basically asked um you know is the
federal reserve's rate cuts are going to
be bullish for the market right even if
they do start cutting rates eventually
is that going to be bullish for the
market well the short answer is yes the
long answer is it's not so easy it's a
little bit more complicated because the
only reason why the Federal Reserve
starts cutting rates in the first place
is if there is some type of a problem
right there there's a problem they're
trying to fix right every time you go
back every time the Federal Reserves cut
rates they're they're fighting either
recession or deflation or both right now
we don't have anything right we don't
have a recession we don't have an
economic recession the labor Market's
too tight for that we don't have
deflation by any means uh inflation
still stickier so there's no reason
there's no incentive for the Federal
Reserve to to start cutting rates just
yet right that's why I've been a little
bit more on the fence I've been like
okay maybe maybe the Federal Reserve can
raise interest rates maybe one more time
another 25 basis points um is a
possibility although Market disagrees
because the Market's pricing in a pause
uh all the way through the end of the
year and they're expecting Cuts next
year now again we'll find out
considering how tight the labor market
is considering how stickier the
inflation is I just I I don't I don't
think the markets uh Market's correct
but again I could be wrong and the
Federal Reserve may end up pausing for
the rest of the year and then start
cutting in 2024 but the idea for cuts is
very much the need and incentive they
need something that need to fix and
until we get that right they're not
going to in my opinion they're going to
keep rates higher for longer maybe maybe
they don't hike maybe they keep them
where they are but they are going to
keep them where they are for longer
until inflation is down to their Target
because they're very very adamant
they're very persistent and they're not
taking their foot off the gap gas until
it comes down to 2% because the last
thing they want to see is a double top
on inflation similar to what we
witnessed back in the 1970s and 1980s
the great inflation of 80s where
inflation was up it came down the
Federal Reserve eased back a little bit
and then it spiked right back up right
so the last thing they want to see is a
double top uh on inflation and a double
dip recession so they want to put it
down and they want to put it down for
good right remember we talking about
inflation so when they do start cutting
rates they're probably doing that in in
terms of fighting something which is
either recession or deflation which is
not great for the economy which is not
great for the market in the short term
but eventually being a very very good
Catalyst and we do get a very nice
window of buying opportunity um during
that time because at the end of the day
I mean you know on the surface level
rate cuts are quantitative easing they
are a way of quantitative easing they
are a way of stimulating the economy and
that creates that window of buying
opportunity which eventually the market
realizes then it starts pushing higher
similar to what we witnessed in 2020
similar s what we witnessed in 2018
similar to what we had witnessed in 2011
similar to what like literally every
single time we've gone through these
rate cut Cycles the markets have reacted
positively eventually maybe not in the
short term but eventually they have so
that was uh you know the answer to that
question and now going over to some of
these numbers so this is the Atlanta's
fed sticky price CPI so sticky price
inflation a measure of things such as
rents and various services and insuring
cost ran 5.1% in September num so that's
a little bit higher than the overall
headline and core CPI as well uh because
these are stickier inflation numbers
like insurance insurance costs rents uh
some of these other items that are
considered to be more sticky than others
um and we've got flexible CPI which does
include food energy vehicle cost apparel
ran at just 1% rate so you kind of see
like what really is the cul rate what's
really moving lower what's really
actually moving higher um and it's rents
and it's Insurance Services some of the
stickier items so again you can see
shelter was up 6% month over month 7.2%
year over-ear uh food prices up 0 2%
month over month 3.7% year-over-year and
fuel oil as discussed in our previous
updates
88.5% month over month and still down
right still in deflation um at the
moment so even though we are seeing
deflation from energy we're seeing
disinflation from food and we're seeing
a very very moderate disinflation from
shelter but uh but it's not really uh
showing signs of of of selling off
pretty aggressively so that to a point
where inflation overall starts coming
down now another report mortgage rates
hit 23-year highs and home prices show a
few signs of cooling um so again we
talked about this you know during our
live stream as well that this is the
widest Gap one of the widest gaps that
we are witnessing between the buyer and
the seller when it comes to real estate
and uh it's unfortunate because uh
mortgage rates are hitting their highest
levels and the cost of boring are is
extremely high right and and until that
market normalizes a little bit I think
rents are going to be under pressure now
this right here is the state of the
market so big Tech was flat right we
didn't really see a lot of momentum in
either direction um meta here down
Google down 1% Tesla's down over one and
a half Apple's down half Microsoft's
down 38 basis points Amazon's up 308
basis points broadcom we did have
semiconductors push higher so clack uh
Corporation lamb research Applied
Materials broadcom Adobe they all pushed
higher a little bit here on the day uh
but overall we did have a a lot of
stocks selling off including medical
devices uh diagnostic research uh
medical instruments I think a lot of
this sell off could also be regarded to
in mode in mode was down over 20% but in
mode is not such a large corporation to
take down a lot of these companies um
but there was this overall consensus of
negativity um on the medical device
sector because in mode came in with a
lower guidance um for their third
quarter and full year fiscal year
2023 and as a result they obviously did
uh they were down over 20% and some of
the medical device companies were also
selling off here on the day so uh energy
was the only sector that's was somewhat
positive everything else was down in the
last one week we've seen consumer
defensives definitely selling all this
includes your food and beverage
companies including McDonald's Coca-Cola
Pepsi all these companies that were
selling off on the back of that weight
loss drug and the report that came out
of Walmart's executive but overall
everything else is higher 10 out of 11
sectors green and over the last one
month we've got most sectors selling off
except for Comm Services So Meta Google
that are part of Comm Services they're
the only ones that are kind of holding
up orange juice for the win look at that
orange juice up over 2.6% we got cocoa
prices coffee prices gasoline everything
pushing higher with um padium wheat
platinum prices soybeans corn and lumber
prices rolling over Bitcoin still
hovering over 26,000 nether just over
1,500 as well now this right here is the
jobless claims that I also wanted to
talk about and jobless claims numbers
came in at
209,000 uh um and that is a very very
important indicator to watch right it's
a leading indicator uh that basically
tells us when there is a possibility for
recession to start every single time
jobless claims have climbed above a
certain threshold uh unemployment
obviously has followed and that
eventually has led to a recession so the
level that I'm really paying attention
to right now um is going to be closer to
300 to
400,000 uh claims initial claims on a
weekly basis uh because that tends to be
a very very concerning number uh you'll
notice that majority of the times we
actually are below that 400,000
threshold but the moment we start
breaking above you know a recession has
almost always happened um so you can see
that this right here break out over
400,000 recession took place that was
actually during a recession this right
here as soon as we broke out about
400,000 recession uh we were about
400,000 recession we broke out over four
well this right here maybe not so much
we couple times we kind of broke about
400,000 that didn't quite lead to a
recession in 1980s this right here most
certainly in the
1990s again just a few times he kind of
broke out over 400,000 didn't quite see
it as a concerning uh this right here
again in the in the early uh 2000s late
1990s uh again over here 2007 2008 uh
and right now we're nowhere near close
to that 400,000 level just yet so very
very important and leading indicator for
us to pay attention to uh from an
economic standpoint from a labor market
perspective so going over to
uh the S&P 500 you can see that we did
uh sell off here 62 basis points so we
actually came down to 4325 432 so this
right here is actually going to be a
reasonable support uh for the S&P uh you
know kind of validating that support and
then pushing right back up a little bit
back under 4350 but nonetheless we did
pull right back down and as I mentioned
before we're not out of the woods yet
right that's exactly why I wanted to
mention that we are still very much in
the context of this downtrend lower
highs and lower lows yes we got a very
nice Bounce from that 4200 level from
that 200 simple moving average you know
we took a nice trade on tle Q's we took
a nice trade on defense Aerospace
defense sector but uh just looking at it
from the perspective of whether we have
more upside we may we may do we may do
have more upside here but 4450 uh is
going to be that level that lower high
is really going to be that resistance
for S&P moving forward so this right
here is going to be that level and if we
break out above 4500 that's when I'm
going to be a lot more convinced that
okay there is more upside there is
higher highs and higher lows possibility
for S&P 500 but until then there is
still a possibility of this lower highs
and lower lows continuing for the
pattern that's really where we are
that's really how we're trading
volatility here was up over 3.7% so
again a very very muted move to the
upside uh 16.7 so resistance is going to
stay put at 18 and a half closer to 19
levels all the way up to 20 uh Bitcoin
here just uh selling right back down a
little bit over 26,8 800 at the moment
still inside this uptrending channel of
higher highs and higher lows uh right
now so that's what we're watching and
ether uh also just consolidating
sideways at the moment support level
very strong support sitting roughly at
around 1100 uh to watch for ether as
well uh 10year yields uh we're on the
move
4.68% is where we are mortgage rates are
getting up to over 7 and a half for 30y
year 15 years sitting at just under 6.9
uh so again we Contin to see a very very
massive move um in interest rates yields
are kind of moderating a little bit and
that's exactly one of the reasons why we
do have uh a position in TMF and TLT TMF
o down 8% pretty brutal here uh selling
off quite aggressively the 10year yields
uh had a very massive day right so they
were up a little bit over 3% 3% for the
yields pushing back over 4.6 4.7 and of
course as a result TMF was down a little
bit over 8% so very very significant
move uh to the downside for TMF and and
TLT as well we'll talk about this in
more detail in one of our other videos
so next up going to this is going to be
apple let's just go over the NASDAQ
first and NASDAQ here also rolling over
60 basis points again kind of bouncing
off of that support at
13,100 we've had three four consecutive
green days and now we're kind of
approaching that lower High um uh for
the NASDAQ and that's really where the
Bears are going to start to step in and
it's going to get really interesting
whether we you know get rejected or we
break past that resistance so uh this is
going to be that lower high that's the
level to really be paying attention to
for the NASDAQ moving forward Apple here
on the other hand again you can see that
we are perfectly in that lower high so
we are testing $179
$180 and this is the lower high that
that's that's where we are uh at the
moment very much in the context of this
downtrend now if Apple breaks out over
180 um and continues to see that uptrend
uh the next resistance is going to be
somewhere over here at9 closer to $190
um and if applicant break out of this
downtrend that is going to be very good
that's going to obviously put more
pressure um uh more upside pressure on
the markets and the S&P and the NASDAQ
there is a possibility that they also
continue to move higher uh as well and
of course break out those Trends so
Apple here again you know we've got that
lower high sitting roughly around 181 uh
that's going to be that resistance level
to watch talking about Amazon Amazon
here almost filling this entire Gap so
we've got a very very very small Gap
left here but uh pretty much selling off
from highs of 134 coming back down to
132 uh this right here is going to be
that lower high something that we have
discussed in our previous updates that's
the lower high and the lower low for
Amazon and support level is going to
stay roughly in the 12s
12524 for Amazon uh talking about Tesla
here and Tesla here once again you can
see literally just getting Consolidated
and selling off um from that resistance
of around 269 270s so support level is
going to stay put roughly around 256 uh
for Tesla and right now we are very much
in the context of this a little bit of
that symmetrical triangle that's kind of
starting to form where what you'll
notice is that we are getting rejected
at these lower Highs but at the same
time we're getting validated at this
higher low so what we are really seeing
is a lot of uh consolidation and the
pattern continues to Quil in and I think
it's going to be ready for earnings I
think earnings is going to be a big
Catalyst for Tesla for us to see whether
it breaks out or breaks down but right
now down one per on the day getting
rejected two days in a row as mentioned
in our previous Market updates and right
now coming down to its higher low at 250
so it's kind of coiling in uh to make a
very very massive move uh very soon uh
talking about PayPal and PayPal here yet
another low down almost 3% so continues
uh to sell off here still trading in the
context of this lower highs and lower
lows and this falling wedge pattern
earnings earnings earnings is what's
really going to matter with the new CEO
and their vision and what they're
planning to do um to kind of you know
restore some confidence some investor
confidence in the future but right now
definitely selling off almost 3% 56
bucks this right here is going to be
that support level um and of course we
got a resistance sitting all the way up
to 65 to as much as 70 bucks per share
so I think it's just a a waiting game
right now for for PayPal Square on the
other hand has had a very nice reversals
in the last few days I am taking
suggestions folks I think square and
Shopify were going to drop out of these
Market updates and we're going to
replace them with couple new stocks so
it's it's a pretty big decision because
we we uh you know we analyze them on a
regular basis so I want you guys to take
that seriously and there's been a lot of
great suggestions in our Discord so uh
you know let let us know in the comments
if there's any companies you think are
going to be good fit uh they need to be
profitable right it's we've got the same
criterias as the S&P 500 so they need to
be profitable they need to be more
wellestablished companies uh you know
companies that are people are going to
be interested in people that they know
their products and services um so let us
know in the comments which companies can
be replaced uh for for square and
Shopify they're not profitable yet uh
and they're just like having a very hard
time kind of executing on their strategy
and it's been all over the place so
we're going to drop them out for two new
stocks two new companies that I think
would make more sense uh you know given
that we can analyze them every day so
let us know in the comments section down
below uh but but Square here $45 where
it's at I mean it's obviously been
selling off uh obviously Bank I think
came out with a report that this fch
stock has a 60% upside um again
eventually we'll find out if that
actually ends up happening but $52 is
going to be that resistance right now
and uh we've got a moderate support at
around $40 $41 per share talking about
um Nvidia and Nvidia here pushing higher
got rejected a little bit at around $476
$480 so very very nice move uh to the
upside for NVIDIA is pretty much trading
at an all-time high so Nvidia I mean all
hail Nvidia because it's just done
incredibly well um throughout this time
and it's just been consolidating
sideways with a massive support at 400
and a resistance sitting in the 480s and
500 for NVIDIA uh talking about Advanced
Micro Devices also getting a little bit
of that rejection 112 So this right here
is a resistance to watch for Advanced
Micro Devices and right now we are uh
once again getting a little bit of that
resistance there and support level is
going to stay put at 99 close to $100
per share for Advanced Micro Devices so
this right here lower highs and lower
lows of falling wedge pth pattern we got
a very nice breakout a little bit to the
upside but we're not making that higher
high yet no higher high in sight for AMD
just yet support level is going to stay
put at 99 closer to $100 uh meta
platforms uh getting a little bit of
that resistance we did get a decent
breakout so in in theory or in
technicals here yes we did make a new
higher high uh but the price itself also
is a bit more on the overblood side it's
kind of funny because this is actually
one of the fewer names that's actually
overbought right now uh with RSI magd
here pushing higher and support level is
going to stay put at 310 312s for for
meta platforms uh talking about Netflix
here Netflix continues to slide lower so
we are starting to see uh more
breakdowns here for Netflix now trading
below its 200 simple moving average and
the next support is going to be 332 so
this right here is going to be that next
level to watch for for Netflix uh moving
forward that's going to be that level
and Google here uh also pulling back
although validating that support at
13940 so low for the day was 139 45 uh
and we validated that support before
pushing back up to 140 and resistance is
going to stay put roughly at 144 for uh
Google we still have a little bit of
ways to go and the all-time high sits
roughly around 151 uh but Google has
done really well year to date the stocks
up over 56% so incredible gains for
Google Microsoft here uh again just
consolidating sideways so not really
moving all that much uh down about 38
basis points we got a huge resistance
sitting at 340 and a support level is
going to stay up at 3 31 $312 per share
I would still argue that it's still very
much in the context of this downtrend of
lower highs and lower lows and we're not
broken out of that yet uh going over to
nphase energy here n phase also pulling
back from that resistance of 128 129 so
this right here um is a resistance to
pay attention to for end phase and this
is really where that good deal area kind
of sits for us for end phase and finally
Shopify pulling right back down this is
a gap that it eventually needs to fill
in and we've got a support in roughly at
$51 per share for Shopify so hope you
guys enjoyed this video don't forget we
got the money vest talk reports we've
got the uh members only private videos
and the Excel spreadsheets all of that
available including the bind alerts
everything is going to be a part of our
money vest Community make sure that you
do join I've did uh open up a couple
more spots as always if you have any
questions feel free to reach out let us
know what two stocks we can actually
replace for square and Shopify and as
always happy investing and I'll see you
all in the next video and the links are
going to be down below